Finally, we've reached the video exploring
arrays and lists. You may have seen
some previous videos. When we
learn about primitive data types,
object data types, or
even the
auto-boxing technique,
those videos will supplement
this one. First,
you can find the documentation for this video at
this link (I quickly searched on Google and it
came up like this). Besides the
string data type, the
array data type is one of the
most frequently used data types in
your programming career.
For example,
to declare an array,
we usually declare
what type of elements it contains. We use
square brackets like this,
and the array name is on the right, and
its value is on the left. However, when
using arrays, there's a problem:
we are limited in the number of elements,
right? If you
declare an array like this...  So
our network only has a maximum of five
elements; we can never have a
sixth or a seventh element.
Thy Nga, to solve
the problem of the number of elements in our
network, we created an array, a list, or an
array. Besides storing
regular elements like this, it also
stores object variables. So,
later, if you want to store an array
containing data for all students, for example,
this will help you do it. That
's why ERIS was
created. First, we'll talk about the
definition. To
declare an array,
you can use it like this. And to
make it clearer, let's go
into the code. Our video
is video 33, right?
Listen up! Today, inside the
SIC section, I'll give it a new
package. I'll give it a
chapter for, or chapter file.
We've reached chapter f,
and here I'll give it...  Let's create
another class. I'll name it '
video video 33'. Is this really 'video 33'?
Yes, I'll finish it.
We'll close everything else,
and inside this,
first, we'll give it a main function.
Our main function is 'system out', then '
run video 33'. Where are we? I think
from there, and right here,
I'll run it.
This Java Application already has the
text line called 'run video 33'.
Here it is, I have
this text line. Now, let's
declare an array list.
Normally,
you would declare it like this. You have ia =
10 like this, right? We usually
declare an integer variable like this.
Now, to declare an array list,
you can declare it like
this: array list. This is array list. Ah,
actually, I'll change it to Amo, which is '
new radis'.  Yes, there's
something special here,
guys. First, we'll code
it to make it work.
We'll figure that out later.
First, we'll import
this AR list. And if
you click here, you'll find it in the
part called java.yo. This is what
you can imagine as
a method, a class that we
've already written. We
reuse it from the java.tu part.
So, first, we've
declared an array list.
But if you connect the
knowledge, the video I
talked about non-primitive data types,
also known as obsc data types,
applies to this video. Our array is
of the object data type.
So, to create a new object variable,
we need to use a constructor, right?
We need a contractor,
right? So, the part on the right
is where you use it.
Using the constructor, the left side
is where we initialize
an object variable. So from now on,
when you work with
UR, you're actually
working with an object variable.
Here, we declare non-primitive data types like
this, but
in reality, you rarely
code like this. The reason we
don't do that is because when you
declare an `arithm` variable like this,
you don't know
what element it will store. Will it
store an integer, a real number, an
object, or
something else inside? We don't
know, right? Here, I'll
illustrate it further. After
declaring it like this, you can call it `
add string`. Let's
test it. We'll add
elements to it. For example, `
A1`. We'll have a part,
we'll have a part, that's the add part.
Look at this add section. Do
you see anything? It says "
object a". Why doesn't it say "
integer" or
something else? Why does it say "object type"? It
says "object type" because
ERIS works with non-primitive data types,
also known as object data types.
For example, I
wrote "S2" like this, but
here it's not an integer,
you know. It's an integer, you
know. I'm not sure if I wrote it correctly.
Well, for now, it seems like it's an integer like this.
Please note
that this is a primitive data type.
But for ARIS,
we pass it like this.
ARIS's job is to
automatically create a grapper class for you. That's what
I explained in the previous video.
It automatically converts from a
primitive data type to a
non-primitive data type. The only difference is the
capitalization.  This is it, guys. The only
difference is a capital 'y'
and a lowercase 'y'.
This part is non-primitive data types, which
are the data types
defined by our developers,
and this is called the object data type.
This part is just the
regular primitive data type, a
regular integer. I understand that
adding a
regular integer here is still
valid because Arist has a mechanism
called autoboxing; it automatically packages and
converts from one type to another
for you, okay? That's
why, even though we
add an integer like this, it
doesn't throw an error. Similarly, let's
give it something like this. Let's give
it something like 'h'i ...
Okay, let's try the system output and see if
it outputs anything.
Actually, I'll
just replace the `system output` below and let's
print it directly. I'll
use `A1 CH` and `a1.2` as strings. I don't know if
this function will output
anything. I'm not sure if
these two strings will be printed. Let's
run it and see. And there you go, we
've printed it!
You can see that this array
has two elements. Initially, we
declared it as not
defining the number of elements beforehand. Now, if
you want to add
another element, let's say `h IT 2`, for
example. When we run it, we'll see
that we also get `hoi g
t 2`. However, in reality,
you rarely code like this because
if you code like this, the
error checking capability is
quite low.  We don't
know beforehand
what type of value this AR list will store.
For example, you might want
this AR list to only store
string data. So, we want to
code this line, and if
we add an
integer, it will throw an error. This is
what we want to do.
For an AR list, we have another way:
we
can cast the data type.
This way of writing is
called generics.
I'll explain it in more detail in the next video.
But for now, I'll demo it.
I
want this line of code to throw an
error. So, right here in the
AR list line,
you'll give us an
integer. But we don't
write it as 'int' like this; instead,
you'll write it as 'integer' like
this. Then I'll write it like this...
Here's how you can perform parallel type casting on both
sides. We'll do
parallel type casting like this:
after adding the integer,
immediately these two string lines will show an
error.
It tells us that we're using an
integer and we're using a
string. These two data types
are colored similarly. If
we want to avoid this error, please
note that this time we'll use a capital 's' for
integers and a capital 'i' for strings.
Similarly, we'll use 'string'.
I've already introduced this to you.
Our string
is an object data type, but
we use it just like a primitive data type. The
immediate error is that
we're performing type casting.
We want to tell the array list
that we want to store
data of this type. The way we write it is like this
in the video.  Next, I
'll explain in more detail. For those
who want to learn beforehand, I suggest
a keyword: generic.
This is what we call the generic way of writing.
Don't worry, we
'll learn everything in this video. I'm
introducing it, we're going very
slowly, right? A question arises:
what methods does this array have?
You might notice that the first method is
adding an element to
our array. The second method you
often use is to find out
how many
elements are in the array. It supports a
method called `...`.
This is called `...`. It's
not `array chl`.
For array lists, it's called `
array chsi`. Then I'll run it, and
you'll see that we print out the
number 2. This is the array size.  For
those who don't believe me,
I'll show you the third element.
I'll add another element,
so this time when we run it
again, it will show the next three elements.
How do we get the first element?
To get the first element,
we use the `get` method.
We pass in the
element where you want to get it.
We need to pass in the index
of the array. For example, if we want to
get the second element, the second one.
Our array starts from 0,
so we'll pass in
1. Here, if
you hover your mouse over it, you'll
see that the `get` function
requires passing in an
index, right? So here it
will print something. (
Asking IT2 users, right?)
Here I'll also show you a
few other methods. For example,
we want to add, we
want to delete, we want to clear.  We
want to get this. Actually, you
should use the `get` function a
lot. The `delete` function is only
used occasionally. But if
you want to delete everything,
we use the `clear` function.
For example, here we're deleting. The `
delete` function is similar to the `get` function.
Similarly, we need
to specify the index of the array, right?
For example, here we're deleting
the third one. Look, `remove` means we
pass in an object
variable or we pass in the index.
Usually,
you delete by index because that way
we don't need to know what
the value is; we only need to know
where it is in the
array to delete it. For example, here
we're deleting the first one. If
we
delete the first one, what do you think the result will be? The
result is this one.  An
array starts from
0, so the first element corresponds to the
second element, right?
We've deleted that second element, so the
third element will be moved to the top.
Now, let's run it again. You
'll see: Look, our array
has had the second element removed. You
can see that it's no longer asking for
IT2 knowledge. So, the first element will now
ask for IT3 knowledge, right?
These are some of the
methods you're using. Of course,
I won't go from A to Z; all the
methods we have are used with `
arist` because without practical examples,
we won't understand
in the next part of this video.
I'll explain it in more detail.
Why do we code like
this? This is called generics,
and in the next video, I'll guide you
through the basics of generics.